Guide to the Population and Development Program records, 1960-2009.
Population and Development Program records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Population and Development Program records, 1960-2009.
21-33-3765
3 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Reports, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes correspondence, reports and publications.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
In 1962, Joe Mayone Stycos founded the International Population Program, later re-named the Population and Development Program (PDP). Training and research in this program addresses population issues of interest to the United Nations and the World Bank, as well as to national, state and local governments. It promotes collaboration among scholars of diverse disciplines in the Cornell community who teach and conduct research on population issues and relationships and supports graduate training in demography and an undergraduate concentration in population studies.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, reports and publications.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.
Subjects:
Population policy.; Population.; Birth control.; Demography.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- PDP Library History, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- PDP Library History, 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- PDP Seminars, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- PDP Programs "Minutes," and Assorted Papers, 1972-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- PDP Seminars, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- PDP Co-Sponsored Seminars, 1991-2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- C.I.S. Visitors/Speakers Committee, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Annual Reports, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- IPP Brochure and IPP Special Seminar, 1983-1984; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Annual Reports, 1973-1978s (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Parties and Receptions, Assorted, 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Hewlett Grant #99-3676 Final Reports (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Hewlett Grant #2002-7755 and "History of Hewlett Foundation Grants", 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Communication Concerning Archives, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Stycos Celebration Speeches, 6/2/01 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Stycos Celebration, Memory Book Letters, 6/2/01 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Stycos Celebration Invite, Program, Misc., 6/2/01 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Stycos Celebration Audio Cassettes, 6/2/01 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Stycos Celebration Photo Exhibit, 6/2/01 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Stycos Celebration Photos, 6/2/01 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- PDP (IPP) Reprint Series, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Stycos Newspaper Clipping Series, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Stycos Articles, 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Stycos Articles, Conference Papers, and Others, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Stycos Conference Papers, Continuing, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Stycos Assorted, 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Stycos Assorted, 1970s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Walter F. Willcox, Chair (Search for a Chair (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Hewlett Foundation Annual Reports, Plus Ass't., 1984-41989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Hewlett Foundation Annual Reports, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Stycos Report, Puerto Rico; Costa Rica, 1974; 1978 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Stycos Report, Costa Rica (Contraception, Fertility), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Stycos Report, Costa Rican Teenagers (#1), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Stycos Report, Costa Rican Teenagers (#2), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Working Papers (P.D.F.) (1-7), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Stycos Final Report, Costa Rican Teenagers, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Guides to Working Papers, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Sampling of Correspondence RE: Working Papers, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Working Papers (P.D.F.) [8-14], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Working Papers [16-20], 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Working Papers (P.D.P.) [1-7], 1990 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Working Papers (P.D.P.) (8-13), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Working Papers (P.D.P.) (14-20), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Working Papers (P.D.P.) [21-27] 23 Missing, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Working Papers (P.D.P) (1-9), 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Working Papers (P.D.P) (10-18), 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Working Papers (P.D.P), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Working Papers, #3 Missing, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Working Papers (P.D.P) #10 Missing, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Working Papers (P.D.P), 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Working Papers (P.D.P), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Working Papers (P.D.P), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Working Papers (1-9), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Working Papers (P.D.P) (10-18), 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Working Papers (P.D.P), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Working Papers (P.D.P), 2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)